Guide to the Mary Kennedy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Mary Kennedy papers
1894-1988
YCAL MSS 814
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
60
(69 boxes) + 1 record album storage
The papers contain personal and business correspondence, writings, personal papers, and financial records documenting the life and work of the American actress and author Mary Kennedy. Correspondents include her husband American composer Deems Taylor, authors Laura Benét, Pearl S. Buck, and Edna St. Vincent Millay, composer Samuel Barber, fashion designer Valentina, and colleagues from the theater world including Katharine Cornell, Lynn Fontanne, Margalo Gillmore, Helen Hayes, Clare Kummer, Annie Russell, and Marjorie and Roland Young. Family members well represented in the papers are Kennedy's mother Josephine Kennedy Maher, and her brothers James and Foster Kennedy, the latter also an author. Mary Kennedy wrote plays, novels, short stories, poetry, and children's books, and her papers contain drafts, corrected typescripts, and printed versions of her works. Also present are portrait photographs by some of the leading artists of the time, including Arnold Genthe, Ben Magid Rabinovitch, and Edward Steichen, and an autograph manuscript score by Samuel Barber for incidental music to accompany Kennedy's One Day of Spring (1935).
Kennedy, Mary, 1896-1987
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from George Robert Minkoff, Inc. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, the Danford N. Barney, Jr. Fund, and the George B. Alvord Fund, 1988.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 70 contains record album storage. Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Mary Kennedy (1896-1987)
Mary Kennedy was born May 28, 1896, in Claxton, Georgia, the daughter of Edmund Foster Kennedy and Josephine McMahon Kennedy. Following an education in convent schools in Georgia and Florida, she moved to New York and appeared in silent films with the Cosmopolitan Film Company and in several theater productions between 1917 and 1935, including The Barretts of Wimpole Street (1931) with Katharine Cornell. Also a playwright, her first success was Mrs. Partridge Presents, co-authored with Ruth Hawthorne, which was presented on Broadway in 1925 and published by Samuel French. In addition to plays, Kennedy wrote novels, short stories, poetry, and books for children. She was a member of Actors' Equity, the Authors Guild, the Dramatists Guild, the Poetry Society of America, and the Society of Women Geographers.
On June 11, 1921, Kennedy married the American composer Joseph Deems Taylor (1885-1966); their daughter Joan Kennedy Taylor was born in 1926 and the couple divorced in 1934. Mary Kennedy studied at Radcliffe College (1943-1945) and Columbia University (1947-1949), and was awarded three fellowships at the Macdowell Colony. She died on April 24, 1987, in Norwalk, Connecticut.
Scope and Contents
The papers contain personal and business correspondence, writings, personal papers, and financial records documenting the life and work of the American actress and author Mary Kennedy. Correspondents include her husband American composer Deems Taylor, authors Laura Benét, Pearl S. Buck, and Edna St. Vincent Millay, composer Samuel Barber, fashion designer Valentina, and colleagues from the theater world including Katharine Cornell, Lynn Fontanne, Margalo Gillmore, Helen Hayes, Clare Kummer, Annie Russell, and Marjorie and Roland Young. Family members well represented in the papers are Kennedy's mother Josephine Kennedy Maner, and her brothers James and Foster Kennedy, the latter also an author. Mary Kennedy wrote plays, novels, short stories, poetry, and children's books, and her papers contain drafts, corrected typescripts, and printed versions of her works. Also present are portrait photographs by some of the leading artists of the time, including Arnold Genthe, Ben Magid Rabinovitch, and Edward Steichen.
Actors -- United States; Actresses -- United States; American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Children's literature -- 20th Century; Incidental music -- Scores; Theater -- United States; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Sound recordings -- United States -- 20th Century; Studio portraits -- United States -- 20th Century; Actors -- United States -- 20th Century; Actresses -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981; Benét, Laura; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973; Cornell, Katharine, 1893-1974; Fontanne, Lynn, 1887-1983; Genthe, Arnold, 1869-1942; Gillmore, Margalo, 1897-1986; Hayes, Helen, 1900-1993; Kennedy, Foster, 1904-1985; Kennedy, Mary, 1896-1987; Kummer, Clare Beecher, 1886-1958; Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950; Rabinovitch, Ben Magid, 1884-1964; Russell, Annie, 1864-1936; Schlee, Valentina Sanina, 1899-1989; Steichen, Edward, 1879-1973; Taylor, Deems, 1885-1966; Young, Roland, 1887-1953
- December 1988 Acquisition, 60; (69 boxes) + 1 record album storage
  - Letters, Texas, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Letters, including correspondence with Denise Levertov, 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - Past records to 1987 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous business correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - From my desk, receipts and other papers, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Financial diaries, miscellaneous business corr., 1959-1962 (Box 2)
  - "My office", 1953-1954 (Box 3)
  - Notes and drafts of letters, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Income tax return, other papers, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Current business, books and plays, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Work correspondence, Ching-Ling, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Old bank statements, 1950s-1962 (Box 5)
  - Bank statements, New Canaan, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - Bank statements, 1951-1956; 2 (Box 6)
  - Business cards (Box 6)
  - Checkbook (Box 6)
  - Credit cards (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous business papers, 5 (Box 6)
  - Mortgage (Box 6)
  - Receipts, 1956-1975; 4 (Box 6)
  - Seaman's Bank receipts (Box 6)
  - Check stubs, 1951 (Box 6)
  - Portrait photographs, 1930s-1940s (Box 7)
  - Letters (Box 7)
  - Letters from editors (Box 8)
  - Letters, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Letters (Box 8)
  - Business correspondence, 1983 (Box 9)
  - Business, 1961 (Box 9)
  - Business correspondence, 1945-1952 (Box 9)
  - Financial records (Box 10)
  - Letter file: "The beginning of time" (Box 11)
  - Papers, 1955 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence (Box 11)
  - Correspondence (Box 12)
  - Poetry manuscripts (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 2 (Box 13)
  - Jenny, old letters, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Bank statements, 8 (Box 14)
  - Insurance and investment records, 7 (Box 14)
  - Check books, 3 (Box 15)
  - Furnishings, miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Hollow Hill property, Stamford, Connecticut (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous material, includes clippings about her mother (Box 15)
  - Receipts (Box 15)
  - Tax records, 2 (Box 15)
  - Book sales and purchases (Box 16)
  - Copyright information, 2 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, business, miscellaneous, 2 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, drafts of Mary Kennedy's letters to various people, 2 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 3 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence regarding loyalties and publications (Box 16)
  - Correspondence regarding Mary Kennedy's work (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, rejection notices, 3 (Box 16)
  - Eaton, Evelyn, correspondence (Box 16)
  - Feile, Florence, correspondence (Box 16)
  - Le Baron, William, correspondence (Box 16)
  - Real estate leases and deeds (Box 16)
  - "Ride into Morning" business papers (Box 16)
  - "Ride into Morning" clippings, correspondence, publicity (Box 16)
  - Sloane, T. O'Conor III, correspondence (Box 16)
  - Tax records, 1954-1986; 17 (Box 17)
  - "Bus to Nirvana", 12 (Box 18)
  - "Make the Most of Summer", 9 (Box 18)
  - Book ideas (Box 19)
  - "The Captain's on the Bridge," notes, 2 (Box 19)
  - "Charles on Wednesday," notes (Box 19)
  - "Dickie," notes (Box 19)
  - "Look, Look, the Owl!" (Box 19)
  - "McGirr the Cat" (Box 19)
  - "Mrs. Dakara's Dog", 2 (Box 19)
  - "Out of the Wind", 3 (Box 19)
  - "Simon Rides the Wind", 2 (Box 19)
  - "Susan" (Box 19)
  - "Twins," notes (Box 19)
  - "The Visiting Doll", 2 (Box 19)
  - "Araby", 3 (Box 20)
  - "The Bourrichon", 2 (Box 20)
  - "Bring Flowers of the Rarest" (Box 20)
  - "Circle the Green Earth", 9 (Box 20)
  - "The Cousins" (Box 20)
  - "The End of the Beginning", 2 (Box 20)
  - "First Love" (Box 20)
  - "The Golden Flower" (Box 20)
  - "The Homeless" (Box 20)
  - "Jarvis had a Gypsy Wife", 2 (Box 20)
  - "Journey East", 3 (Box 20)
  - "Little Lions in the Tall Grass" (Box 20)
  - "Make the Most of Summer" (Box 20)
  - "Mary Ann's Mauve Spring" (Box 20)
  - "More Precious than Rubies" (Box 20)
  - "My Friend Christopher" (Box 20)
  - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 20)
  - "O, Professor!", notes (Box 20)
  - "The Pool with Reflection" (Box 20)
  - "Sales Talk" (Box 20)
  - Stories, 5 (Box 20)
  - "Such a Little Fence" (Box 20)
  - "The Vacant Lot"/"The Lot on the Corner" (Box 20)
  - "Come and See Me!" (Box 21)
  - Kennedy, Foster, "The Disappearance of Mr. Allan" (Box 21)
  - "The King and Queen of Megolissa" (Box 21)
  - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 21)
  - River, secret, 3 (Box 21)
  - "The Terror in the Walls of the House Beside the River" (Box 21)
  - "A Surprise to the Children" (Box 21)
  - "Violets are Blue", 5 (Box 21)
  - "Wings" (Box 21)
  - "Emily and the Green Circle", 7 (Box 22)
  - "Jenny", 18 (Box 22)
  - A Star on her Forehead, with Helen Hayes, 3 (Box 22)
  - "Emmy and the Green Circle", 4 (Box 23)
  - "Question the night", 4 (Box 23)
  - A Star on her Forehead, with Helen Hayes (book), 2 (Box 23)
  - Jenny, Sam and the Invisible Hildegarde (book) (Box 23)
  - Question the Night (book) (Box 23)
  - Emily and the Green Circle (book) (Box 23)
  - Jenny (book) (Box 23)
  - "Behind the Day", 5 (Box 24)
  - "New Green over Old Green" (Box 24)
  - Poems (Box 24)
  - "Ride into Morning", 5 (Box 24)
  - Behind the Day (book) (Box 24)
  - New Green over Old Green (book) (Box 24)
  - "I am a Thought of You," letters, 1968-1969 (Box 25)
  - "Translations from the Chinese Sie Thao" (Box 25)
  - "Sie Thao", 1968 (Box 25)
  - "Jordan", 11 (Box 26)
  - "Mrs. Partridge Presents", 3 (Box 26)
  - "Never Look Back", 13 (Box 26)
  - "Christie", 14 (Box 27)
  - "Quirly Daffle", 10 (Box 27)
  - "The Lizard", 16 (Box 28)
  - "Princess Thida: a Tale of Courage", 10 (Box 28)
  - "The Rich Young Ruler" (Box 28)
  - "Shulo", 6 (Box 28)
  - "The Meeting of Confucius and Lao-Tzu", 16 (Box 29)
  - "So Many Butterflies", 17 (Box 29)
  - "An Affair of Discretion" (Box 30)
  - "The Chameleon" (Box 30)
  - "The Fledgling", 4 (Box 30)
  - "Heart's Blood", 6 (Box 30)
  - "Home James", 3 (Box 30)
  - "Sylvie", 6 (Box 30)
  - "Teddy's Wives"[?] (Box 30)
  - "Cranford", 14 (Box 31)
  - "The Laurels are Cut", 11 (Box 31)
  - "Ching-Ling and the Magic Peach", 3 (Box 32)
  - "The Lady Loro", 6 (Box 32)
  - "The Lepers' Revolt", 5 (Box 32)
  - "Ming Yee", 4 (Box 32)
  - "Nora", 8 (Box 32)
  - "To Buy Heaven", 7 (Box 32)
  - "The Arbor of the Floating Wine Cups", 7 (Box 33)
  - "The Bourrichon" (Box 33)
  - "Circle the Green Earth", 2 (Box 33)
  - "Drawings of Oriental Scenes" (Box 33)
  - "The Goat that Lived by Himself", 15 (Box 33)
  - "Kara", 2 (Box 33)
  - "New Green over Old Green" (Box 33)
  - "Nora" (Box 33)
  - Notes for poetry series (Box 33)
  - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 33)
  - "One of the Sidhe" (Box 33)
  - Poetry manuscripts, miscellaneous, 9 (Box 33)
  - "Ride into Morning" (Box 33)
  - Address lists (Box 34)
  - Journal (Box 34)
  - Notebooks, 5 (Box 34)
  - Scratch pads (Box 34)
  - Notebooks (Box 34)
  - Notebooks (Box 34)
  - Addresses (Box 35)
  - "Ching-Ling and the Magic Peach" (Box 35)
  - Correspondence (Box 35)
  - Lists, miscellaneous, 2 (Box 35)
  - Notes [journal] (Box 35)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 15 (Box 35)
  - Notes, poetry (Box 35)
  - Notes, prose, 4 (Box 35)
  - Notes, research, 2 (Box 35)
  - Story ideas (Box 35)
  - Anderson, Jane: correspondence with Mary Kennedy and Deems Taylor (Box 36)
  - [Auto?]biographical material, 2 (Box 36)
  - Clippings, programs and miscellaneous correspondence (Box 36)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous (Box 36)
  - Cranford [Fanny?] notes (Box 36)
  - "The Crows," notes (Box 36)
  - "The Engagement," notes (Box 36)
  - Quiterman, Arthur, notes for prologue (Box 36)
  - Howard, Peter, "Ideas Have Legs" (Box 36)
  - Hsiang Fei, 2 (Box 36)
  - "Jeremy and Clare" (Box 36)
  - Kennedy, Foster, 3 (Box 36)
  - "Lady Lord" (Box 36)
  - Notes, drama, miscellaneous, 4 (Box 36)
  - Notes for children's stories (Box 36)
  - Notes for "Christy," poetry manuscripts, miscellaneous (Box 36)
  - Notes on the Aymara Indians of Bolivia (Box 36)
  - Notes on sister Juana Ines de la Cruz (Box 36)
  - Notes for Catherine Valois, Crisis (Box 36)
  - Notes, short stories, miscellaneous (Box 36)
  - Notes, writing, miscellaneous, 9 (Box 36)
  - Reader's Digest entries (Box 36)
  - Poems by Mary Kennedy set to music (Box 36)
  - "A Present for Miguel" (Box 36)
  - "Question the Night" (Box 36)
  - "River Secret," discards (Box 36)
  - "Sally and George" (Box 36)
  - "Poor Simon," letters regarding Sept. 1957 issue of Jack and Jill (Box 36)
  - "The Searching Heart" (Box 36)
  - Short story drafts (Box 36)
  - Short works, "The Brothers" (Box 36)
  - Story ideas (Box 36)
  - Studio for Mary Kennedy (Box 36)
  - "Talk to the Young" (Box 36)
  - Taylor, Deems, "Paris" (Box 36)
  - "Thee Men on a Raft," clipping (Box 36)
  - "True Stories" (Box 36)
  - Charles, notes (Box 37)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 5 (Box 37)
  - Notes, writing, miscellaneous, 1950-1979; 18 (Box 37)
  - Arlen, Michael, The Green Hat (signed) (Box 38)
  - Asia Institute, correspondence (Box 38)
  - The Barretts of Wimpole Street program (Box 38)
  - Clippings, miscellaneous, 2 (Box 38)
  - Clippings, programs, reviews (Box 38)
  - Correspondence regarding China (Box 38)
  - Correspondence with publishers, miscellaneous (Box 38)
  - How to write a synopsis (Box 38)
  - "In My Tent," poem by Mary Kennedy (Box 38)
  - "Kara," notes (Box 38)
  - Lists, miscellaneous (Box 38)
  - "Mariners" (Box 38)
  - Mrs. Partridge Presents (Box 38)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 4 (Box 38)
  - Notes for "Story for a Chill", 2 (Box 38)
  - Notes on poems for Gotham Book Mart series (Box 38)
  - Notes on writing (Box 38)
  - Notes taken at the Philharmonic (Box 38)
  - Poetry manuscripts by others (Box 38)
  - Programs, passes, membership cards (Box 38)
  - "Ride into Morning" (Box 38)
  - Rose, Amy, poetry manuscripts (Box 38)
  - Royalty statements (Box 38)
  - Deems Taylor, "Peter Ibbetson" (Box 38)
  - "Wings and other children's books" (Box 38)
  - "Singing," cover featuring Deems Taylor (Box 38)
  - "Alexander Woolcott" (Box 39)
  - [Auto?]biographical material (Box 39)
  - Awards (Box 39)
  - Canalla, Mary June, correspondence. Includes poems by Patrick Mooney (Box 39)
  - Clippings, miscellaneous, 4 (Box 39)
  - Clippings of published poems, 3 (Box 39)
  - Conservation pledge competition (Box 39)
  - Correspondence regarding hearing aids (Box 39)
  - Correspondence regarding Inez Renn (Box 39)
  - Creative arts and faith workshop (Box 39)
  - "Jenny," miscellaneous material, including corr with Adrienne Adams (Box 39)
  - Kennedy, Foster, fan mail (Box 39)
  - Notes for radio programs designed to sell war bonds (Box 39)
  - Notes for Theatre of the Air (Box 39)
  - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 39)
  - P.E.N. miscellaneous lists (Box 39)
  - Poetry workshop, miscellaneous (Box 39)
  - Professional associations, miscellaneous, 2 (Box 39)
  - Review of Billmyer show (Box 39)
  - Reviews, 2 (Box 39)
  - Songs for children (Box 39)
  - Writings by others, 2 (Box 39)
  - "Behind the Day", 2 (Box 40)
  - "The Bourrichon", 5 (Box 40)
  - "Ching-Ling and the Magic Peach", 5 (Box 40)
  - Clippings of notices of Mary Kennedy's works (Box 40)
  - "Come and See Me" (Box 40)
  - "Emily and the Green Circle" (Box 40)
  - "Jenny," publicity material and corr. (Box 40)
  - Kennedy, Foster, "The Disappearance of Mr. Allan" (Box 40)
  - "New Green Over Old Green" (Box 40)
  - "Princess Thida" (Box 40)
  - "Question the Night" (Box 40)
  - Reviews of Mary Kennedy's poetry; includes letter from Padraic Colum (Box 40)
  - "Ride into Morning" (Box 40)
  - "Shulo, or How the Animals Dug their Well" (Box 40)
  - "Violets are Blue" (Box 40)
  - Buck, Pearl S., 8 (Box 41)
  - Correspondence regarding "The Empress" (Box 41)
  - Clippings by and about Edna St. Vincent Millay and Deems Taylor (Box 41)
  - La Farge, C. Grant: drawing of plan for St. John the Divine (Box 41)
  - La Farge, C. Grant, and Mary Kennedy: "The Rainbow Collection" (Box 41)
  - La Farge, C. Grant, and Mary Kennedy: "Shadows", 3 (Box 41)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, "The Casket of Glass" (Box 41)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent and Deems Taylor: "The King's Henchman", 2 (Box 41)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, "Conversation at midnight" (Box 41)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent,"The princess marries the page", 3 (Box 41)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, publications by and about (Box 41)
  - Photograph of Edna St. Vincent Millay and Mary Kennedy (Box 41)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent and Eugen Boissevain: correspondence (Box 41)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent and Eugen Boissevain: correspondence with Deems Taylor (Box 41)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent and Anne Boissevain: correspondence; includes photographs of Edna St. Vincent Millay (Box 41)
  - TLS from [H-?] to Judy (Box 41)
  - Accounts, 1927-1928 (Box 42)
  - Dane, Clemence, "Will Shakespeare", 1922 (Box 42)
  - Mary Kennedy clippings and photos (Box 42)
  - Taylor Deems, "Gandle", 1928; 2 (Box 42)
  - Obey, Andre, "Lucrece" (Box 42)
  - Taylor, Deems: last will and testament (Box 42)
  - Deems Taylor and Mary Kennedy correspondence, 1920-1963; 30 (Box 42)
  - Taylor, Deems, miscellaneous (Box 42)
  - Taylor, Deems, "Peter Ibbetson", 1930; 2 (Box 42)
  - Taylor, Deems, "Plans for house" (Box 42)
  - Photo album, 2 (Box 43)
  - Photographs of Clare Kummer, Marjorie Kummer Young, and Roland Young (Box 43)
  - Kummer, Clare, correspondence, 2 (Box 43)
  - Young, Marjorie Kummer, correspondence, 5 (Box 43)
  - Correspondence regarding "Jordan" (Box 44)
  - Cornell, Katharine and Guthrie McClintic, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Coward, Noel, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Fontanne, Lynn and Alfred Lunt, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Frost, Lesley, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Gillmore, Margalo, correspondence, 2 (Box 44)
  - Hastings, Ross, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Hawthorne, Ruth, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Hayes, Helen, correspondence (Box 44)
  - La Farge, C. Grant, Florence and Christopher, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Le Baron, William, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Lewis, Mabel Terry, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Lin Yutang (Box 44)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Menotti, Gian Carlo, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Merrill, James, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Milford, Nancy, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Moore, Marianne, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Moore, Matthew, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Murray, Natalia Danesi, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Murray, Gilbert, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Niles, Blair, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Perry, Antoinette, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Pruitt, Ida, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Shirer, William L., correspondence (Box 44)
  - Skinner, Cornelia Otis, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Steward, Donald Ogden, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Straight, Beatrice, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Tuttle, Day, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Valentina, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Van Doren, Mark, correspondence (Box 44)
  - Aherne, Brian, correspondence (Box 45)
  - Ames, Lucy and Winthrop, correspondence (Box 45)
  - Barney, Maginel Wright, correspondence (Box 45)
  - Bok, Curtiss, and Nellie Lee, correspondence (Box 45)
  - Bok, Mary, correspondence (Box 45)
  - Brackett, Charles, correspondence (Box 45)
  - Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg, correspondence (Box 45)
  - Bute, Mary Ellen, correspondence (Box 45)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 2 (Box 45)
  - MacDougall, Allan Ross, correspondence (Box 45)
  - Tracy, Louise and Susie, correspondence, 2 (Box 45)
  - Wood, Peggy, correspondence (Box 45)
  - Barber, Samuel, correspondence (Box 46)
  - Bok, Mary, correspondence (Box 46)
  - Le Gallienne, Eva, correspondence (Box 46)
  - "One Day of Spring," with Samuel Barber, 1935; 6 (Box 46)
  - Russell, Annie, correspondence (Box 46)
  - Benét, Laura, correspondence and photo (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, 5 (Box 47)
  - Notes and correspondence regarding records and registration at Radcliffe (Box 48)
  - Notes, fine arts, 2 (Box 48)
  - Notes, history (Box 48)
  - Notes, linguistics (Box 48)
  - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 48)
  - Notes on China (Box 48)
  - Papers from Radcliffe (Box 48)
  - Papers, philosophy (Box 48)
  - Photographs of Mary Kennedy's sculpture (Box 48)
  - Filmer chart (Box 49)
  - "Mother" (clippings) (Box 49)
  - "Marriage this evening" (clipping) (Box 49)
  - Clipping about 1927 "Mariners," Plymouth Theatre (Box 49)
  - Theatre (clippings) (Box 49)
  - Clippings, miscellaneous (Box 49)
  - Photographs of Mary Kennedy, clippings (Box 49)
  - "Very early memories" (Box 49)
  - Letters, clippings, map of Arizona (Box 49)
  - Lock of Josephine Kennedy Maner's hair (Box 49)
  - Scrapbooks, 2 (Box 49)
  - Photographs: family, stills of Mary Kennedy and others (Box 49)
  - "Portrait of my mother as a little girl", misc (Box 49)
  - Clippings, 2 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, letters to Josephine Kennedy Maner (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous (Box 49)
  - Kennedy James: diaries, enlistment papers (Box 49)
  - Address book (Box 49)
  - Medals, etc. of Foster Kennedy (Box 49)
  - Prayer book (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 12 (Box 50)
  - Correspondence regarding Mary Kennedy's work (Box 50)
  - [?], Florida, correspondence (Box 51)
  - [B-] Edith (Box 51)
  - Bozyan, Edith, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Butler, William, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Carter, Dagny, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous (Box 51)
  - [D.-] Angela, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Dutton, Louise, and family, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Felicitas, Sr. M. Correspondence (Box 51)
  - Gallup, Donald, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Goss, Madeleine, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Ivans, Elaine, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Jenison, Madge, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Keen, Helen, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Landon, Frederica, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Marquette, Jacques de, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Mian, Mary, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Nolt, Stanley, correspondence (Box 51)
  - O'Higgins, Monica, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Patrick, Gladys Baker, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Pentland, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Porter, Lucy, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Taylor, Anne, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Waldron, Patricia, correspondence (Box 51)
  - Christmas cards, 1960, 1964 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 9 (Box 52)
  - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 52)
  - Travel tickets, receipts, information, 1935-1936; 2 (Box 52)
  - Archer, Sebastian, correspondence (from China) (Box 53)
  - Ivans, Claire, correspondence (Box 53)
  - Kelley, Ethel M., correspondence (Box 53)
  - Moore, Mary, correspondence, 4 (Box 53)
  - Ladd, Valeria, correspondence (Box 53)
  - Letters (Box 53)
  - Kennedy family miscellaneous correspondence (Box 54)
  - Kennedy, Edmund Foster, and Josephine (parents of Mary Kennedy), correspondence, 1894-1895 (Box 54)
  - Kennedy, Foster, correspondence, miscellaneous (Box 54)
  - Kennedy, Foster, correspondence with Mary Kennedy (Box 54)
  - Kennedy, James, correspondence (Box 54)
  - Kennedy, James, correspondence with Mary Kennedy (Box 54)